CHRIS SANFORD

SR. UI/UX DESIGNER

303-929-4367 keelersanford@gmail.com https://ckeelers.github.io/portfolio

Designing and creating highly memorable, emotional, and best-in-class customer experiences that users need and love to use is what drives my creative passion as a designer. With over 10 years of experience, I am intimately familiar with the design process, having lead teams of designers to collaborate on initiatives through every phase of the process with a focus on strategic design thinking, all while critically ensuring great care and empathy through the lense of the user.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Sr. UI/UX Designer | DHI Group, Inc. - Sept. 2016 - present DHI is the parent company of career platforms Dice, Clearance Jobs, and eFinancial Careers.

- Lead the redesign of the Dice.com experience through an iterative design process
 that included the complete re-envisioning of the visual design language for Dice,
 greatly improving user engagement and new user registrations.
- Responsible for leading the planning and strategic approach for a design system, collaborating closely with product and technology to improve consistency and speed-to-market, while adhering to newly established principles and guidelines through a foundation of user experience. This required being acutely aware of technical constraints, scope and promoting adoption across the organization.
- Working closely with executive leadership, I spearheaded the redesign of the corporate DHI website to better showcase company brands while allowing simpler, easier navigation for investors and corporate interests.
- Lead efforts to implement a responsive redesign of eFinancialCareers.com, increasing mobile traffic and improving the user experience across devices and platforms.
- Lead the iterative approach to a complete redesign of the candidate search experience on Dice, through close collaboration with senior stakeholders, UX, and product to vastly improve performance and user engagement.
- Work to plan, strategize, and create a vision for features and enhancements by applying design thinking methodologies to better understand user problems and discover solutions through iterative design, while providing mentorship to new and mid-level designers.

Sr. Web Designer | ShopAtHome.com - Feb. 2012 - Aug 2016 ShopAtHome is a coupon and cash back website specializing in retail discounts and rewards.

- Assisted in the redesign of the ShopAtHome.com experience and lead a team of
 designers and software developers on implementing a responsive framework with
 a focus on a mobile-first user experience, successfully improving performance
 and increasing mobile engagement.
- Lead the efforts to design the first mobile app for ShopAtHome.com on both iOS and Android platforms, working closely with developers as well as product and marketing teams to incorporate various features and company vision, while adhering to iOS and Android design standards and company design guidelines.

Game UI Designer | Masque Publishing, Inc. - Mar. 2007 - Nov 2011

Masque is a developer and publisher of online slots and table style games

- Created engaging user interface designs for top-rated online games featured on AOL games.com and Facebook for both desktop and mobile platforms.
- Developed identity and branding including logos, color composition, icons, and other visual elements.
- Designed and coordinated implementation of in-game advertising promotions for clients such as Cottonelle, Sprint, and Pepsi Cola.

SKILLS

Visual Design

Clear understanding of information architecture and user-centered design practices, heuristics, usability and accessibility, establishing visual guidelines and branding; acute attention to detail in color, typography, and composition.

User Experience

Highly experienced in the design process and the software development lifecycle, including research & discovery, the creation of user scenarios, stakeholder and customer interviews, low-fidelity wireframes, rapid prototyping and user testing, user-flows, and high-fidelity visual design from initial concept to finished product.

Experienced in planning and executing design thinking workshops with stakeholders, presenting research and findings to UX as well as senior and executive leadership.

Tools & Technologies

Sketch, Figma, Zeplin, Invision, Miro, Adobe Creative Suite, html5, css3, Sass, git, native design for Android/ iOS, Responsive web design. Working knowledge of javascript.

Education

Art Institute of Colorado BA in Interactive Media Design 2001 - 2005